<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning 2022 on MCPT Learning Resources</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/</link><description>Recent content in Learning 2022 on MCPT Learning Resources</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Holiday Game Jam II</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/holiday-game-jam-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/holiday-game-jam-ii/</guid><description>Game Jam The return of William Lyon Mackenzie&amp;rsquo;s Holiday Game Jam!
Create a game with your team of up to 4 friends over 108 hours for a chance to win prizes!
Itinerary Dates and Times The competition will run from 12:00PM December 26th to 11:59PM December 30th. Teams will have the full 108 hours to design a game and pitch. Note that you may only start working on your project once the competition window begins on December 26th at noon.</description></item><item><title>Game Dev Workshop</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/game-development-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/game-development-workshop/</guid><description>Resource page for game development workshop hosted by MCPT Learning Branch.
A two-part series teaching you how to create a dodging game. No previous experience is required, so whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner to game-development or have tons of experience, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to enjoy the workshop. Get started by visiting the workshop pages and downloading the attached files below to learn how to create a dodging game in Processing.</description></item><item><title>Web Dev Workshop</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/web-development-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/learning-2022/web-development-workshop/</guid><description> Resource page for web development workshop hosted by MCPT Learning Branch.
Check Out: Frontend Useful Pages: Opening HTML Files Editing HTML Files Lesson References: Frontend Slideshow Presentation Demo Site Link Demo Site for download Backend Slideshow Presentation Further Learning/Useful Sites: HTML Documentation CSS Documentation Github W3Schools HTML - Helpful resource for learning W3Schools CSS - Helpful resource for learning StackOverflow - Forum with plenty of questions and answers</description></item></channel></rss>