<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jumping Physics Workshop on MCPT Learning Resources</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/jumpingphysics/</link><description>Recent content in Jumping Physics Workshop on MCPT Learning Resources</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/jumpingphysics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Collisions</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/jumpingphysics/collisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/jumpingphysics/collisions/</guid><description>Collisions are one of the most important and fundamental aspects of game development. Based on when and how certain things collide, events occur to make the game dynamic and fun to play. In this lesson, we will go over how to implement collisions in our demo.
Theory Behind Collisions Collisions in any game are all about the type of the collision and its subsequent event. For example, if a player jumps and there is a block above him, the upward collision (type) triggers a change in the player’s trajectory (event).</description></item><item><title>Jumping Physics</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/jumpingphysics/jumpingphysics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/jumpingphysics/jumpingphysics/</guid><description>Jumping is a very common mechanic in games (especially platformers). In this workshop you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to implement this mechanic in processing, which can be transferred to other languages. Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to check for collisions in jumps.
Basics of Jumping in Games In our platformer-style game, we control the user&amp;rsquo;s jumps by pressing the up button (holding the button for a higher jump) and then the square (character) jumps upwards and then comes back down to the floor.</description></item></channel></rss>