<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on MCPT Learning Resources</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on MCPT Learning Resources</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Github Crash Course</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/github/</guid><description>Brought to you by MCPT : )
What is Git &amp;amp; Github? Git is a version control system which helps individuals as well as teams keep track of their code as it is created. Notable functions include reverting back to a previous state of code, creating a separate &amp;ldquo;branch&amp;rdquo; of code to add changes, and merging branches when changes are completed and tested. All in all, Git is something all developers should know.</description></item><item><title>Devpost Information</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/devpost-info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/devpost-info/</guid><description>Welcome to the Holiday Game Jam! In this document, you will find all the information required in order to prepare for the submission of your hack!
Step 1: Creating a Devpost Account If you have not already done so, the first thing you need to do is register for a Devpost account. Simply head over to https://devpost.com/ and click the &amp;ldquo;Sign-up&amp;rdquo; button on the top right.
You will have the option of signing up with your Google, Facebook, LinkedIn, Email, or Github account.</description></item><item><title>Tips &amp; Tricks</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/tips/</guid><description>Welcome to the Holiday Game Jam! In this document, you will find information to help you get started with your project, especially if this is your first time participating in a Hackathon or Game Jam.
Idea Creation For the Holiday Game Jam, you are free to create an idea on whatever you like! You are by no means restricted to a set of rules, as Game Jams are very open-ended and allow for coming up with as unique and creative ideas as you want.</description></item><item><title>Pitch Creation</title><link>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/pitch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://learning.mcpt.ca/game-jam/resources/pitch/</guid><description>Congratulations everyone! As we make it through the last stretch of the Holiday Game Jam, it’s just about time to prepare an offline presentation in order to compliment your Devpost submission, and maximize your chances of standing out!
In case you haven’t read through it already, it is highly recommended to take a look at our Devpost Info &amp;amp; Submission Requirements Document if you’re having any difficulty setting up your main submission.</description></item></channel></rss>